# **Jude Suthagar SUBRAMANIAM**

**Experienced Operations Assistant | Powercoders Participant** 

Gurtenmundstrasse 9, 6460 Altdorf, UR

jude.subramaniam@powercoders.org | +41 77 94 25 109

Date of Birth: 27 October 1977 | Civil status: Married | Residence permit B

GitHub | Learning Blog | linkedIn

Languages: English (C1), German (B2), Sinhala (B2), Tamil (mother tongue)

IT skills: Beginner: HTML, CSS, GitHub, Filmora



# **PROFILE**

Organized operational professional with 12+ years of experience in the international environment supporting business areas such as Administration, IT, Finance, Human Resources and Logistics. Collaborative team player with strong management, communication, decision making, planning and organizational, analytical and time management skills. Independent and flexible work attitude

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

11/2003 – 07/2015

## Operations Assistant, UNICEF, Batticaloa, Sri Lanka

The United Nations (UN) mission to Sri Lanka was due to the civil war and Tsunami. The UN mission had more than 10 agencies working in the field. I managed the office operations of one of the UNICEF field offices in all the aspects of Admin, IT, Finance, HR, Logistics and Security.

- Executed various administrative tasks, including travel arrangements, hotel bookings, managing phone calls, correspondence and records of assets
- Supervised operations staff and provided coaching, disciplining, monitoring and appraising job results.
- Carried out various IT tasks such as basic data & voice network troubleshooting, daily server backup, installation & configuration of network devices (Printers, Scanner) and organizing AV conferencing via Polycom.
- Used VISION (SAP based application) for daily business.
- Developed, planned and implemented legally adherent and cost-effective procedures for the office operation and reduced operating costs.
- Efficiently handled a variety of accounting activities such as Petty cash management, budgeting, payment documents and bank reconciliations
- Human Resource duties consisted in conducting recruitment, new employee orientation, benefits administration and exit interviews.
- Provided payroll information by monitoring attendance, overtime sheets and leave records.
- Assisted in the processing of contracts for consultants and institutional contractors.
- Conducted bidding and procurement
- Handled warehousing and supply distribution.
- Managed office vehicle fleet and maintained system to monitor vehicle repairs and maintenance.

04/2002 – 04/2003 Technical Assistant, Ministry of Projects & Maintenance, Sohar, Oman

The ministry of P&M maintains the Royal Palaces and I assisted the Director General of P&M.

- Managed agenda/appointments of the DGPM
- Served as custodian of the Petty cash
- Prepared and sent progress reports of ongoing constructions to the HO

01/2000 – 03/2002 Computer Operator, Eastern Self-Reliant Community Awakening Organization, Batticaloa, Sri Lanka

ESCO is a local NGO supporting war affected people in many ways. I was mainly assigned to create and maintain electronic files.

- Documented Project proposals
- Maintained records of the credit programs
- Prepared monthly tally sheets and pay abstracts

# **EDUCATION**

09/2020 – 12/2020 Powercoders – Coding Academy for Refugees, Zurich, Switzerland

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming
- Weekly business & social skills training (team work, communication, etc.)

01/2006 – 07/2010 Master of Business Administration, Sikkim Manipal University, Sikkim, India

01/1998 – 12/1999 National Certificate in Accounting Technicien, Technical College, Batticaloa,

Sri Lanka

## **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

04/2017 – present Translator, Swiss Red Cross, Altdorf, Switzerland

Supports the Sri Lankan Refugees in translating documents (English/German

- Tamil), accompanying them to the Immigration and the Hospital

appointments.

01/2019 – present Member, URI Sports Club, Altdorf, Switzerland

Supports the Club in sports activities and social gatherings as event

organizer.

## CERTIFICATION

07/2020 English Language, EF Standard English Test, C2

02/2019 – 05/2019 German Language course, Bénédict-Schule, Luzern B1-B2

07/2013 – 12/2013 Dynamic Leadership Certificate - Prime, Harvard Business Publishing, NY

## **HOBBIES**

Playing Volleyball & Cricket, Cooking and Travelling

# **REFERENCES**

- Hussam Allaham, Powercoders Industry Lead, <a href="mailto:hussam.allaham@powercoders.org">hussam.allaham@powercoders.org</a>, +41 77 906 16 27
- Andrea James, Chief National Committee Relations, Unicef Geneva, <u>ajames@unicef.org</u> +41 79 610 84 86
- Pia Bachmann, Social Worker, Swiss Red Cross, <a href="mailto:pia.bachmann@redcorss.ch">pia.bachmann@redcorss.ch</a>, +41 41 874 09 51